Hunger-Free Pierce County Collaborative United Way of Pierce County 1501 Pacific Ave, Suite 400 Tacoma, WA 98402

#### To Whom It May Concern,

I am enthusiastic to learn more about working as the Coordinator for the Hunger-Free Pierce County Collaborative. Presently, I am a member of the Texas Episcopal Service Corps. I work on a small team to support refugees with complex medical conditions. As my term comes to an end, I aim to begin a second year of service in Olympia. I intend to shift my focus: from medical care to food justice, from direct service to capacity building.

I am interested in the Hunger-Free Pierce County Collaborative because I have volunteered in food banks and outreach kitchens in Boise, San Fransico, and Houston. I also have 3 years of experience in food service, a native competence in organic gardening, and a passion for conscious food culture. Above all, I am motivated to take on new responsibilities in an organization.

A few questions: (i) What is expected of the Coordinator? (ii) Where is the position located? (iii) Who supervises the Coordinator? (iv) At the refugee resettlement agency, an employee is "strong," if they successfully advocate for their client. What makes a "strong" employee at the United Way?

As I have a year of administrative experience in refugee case management, I believe I am a qualified candidate for this position. I am motivated to develop the Hunger-Free Pierce County Collaborative's administrative capacity. In the same way that case management leads a client to self sufficiency, I hope contribute to the sustainable future of Hunger-Free Pierce County Collaborative.

I forward this information with hope to begin a correspondence.

Respectfully,

#### Colton Grainger

P.S. Outside of my professional interests, I am passionate about cycling, hiking, and computer science. I have ambition to pursue higher education in mathematics and, eventually, work towards environmental preservation.

P.P.S. I am available via email, by phone after 3:00 P.M. PST, or by scheduled video-chat.

(208) 585-7373

coltoncgrainger@gmail.com ⋈

coltongrainger.github.io 🖘

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To serve as the Hunger-Free Pierce Country Coordinator through AmeriCorps.

## SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

- 1 year of administrative experience in refugee case management.
- Enthusiasm for food justice, non-profit development, and volunteerism.
- 2 years' expertise in data management.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **B.S.** in Mathematics-Physics

May 2016

The College of Idaho, Caldwell, ID

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Clerk — Refugee Case Management

September 2016 – July 2017

YMCA International Services, Houston, TX

- Supported 7 staff over 240 client cases (60 medical, 180 social adjustment).
- Obtained low-income healthcare for 30 cases and rental assistance for 5 cases.
- Scheduled medical appointments with transportation and interpretation.
- Maintained a resource network of safety-net service providers.

#### **Grading Assistant**

September 2015 – December 2015

The College of Idaho

- Corrected weekly assignments for 25 general physics students.
- Corresponded with faculty to ensure objective and accurate grading.

#### Dishwasher & Server

Summers 2012, 2013, Fall 2015

The Griddle, Meridian, ID

- Kept clean a 600 ft<sup>2</sup> commercial kitchen.
- Trained new staff for the front of house and kitchen.

# COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

#### **Service Corps Fellow**

August 2016 – July 2017

Texas Episcopal Service Corps, Houston, TX

- Completed a year of service (1,800 hours) while living in community.
- Participated in professional development and communication training.

#### Dean — Gem Boys State

June 2014 and 2015

Northwest Nazerene University, Nampa, ID

• Coordinated a summer camp on state government (150 students).

#### JOB RELATED COMPETENCIES (rated out of 5)

#### Social Service

- Conflict resolution (4) I
- Volunteer recruitment (3)

#### Technology

- Microsoft Office (5)
- HTML5, CSS, LATEX (5)

#### Communication

- Public speaking (4)
- Website hosting (4)
- Graphic design (5)
- Grant writing (3)
- Event planning (3)

## **Professional References**

Shaoli Bhadra Refugee Medical Care Program Coordinator

- work: 713-339-9015 ext. 1051
- cell: 704-651-3610
- email: shaoli.bhadra@ymcahouston.org

### Salimah Shamsuddin Refugee Case Management Program Coordinator

- work: 713-339-9015 ext. 1019
- cell: 205-585-0362
- email: salimah.shamsuddin@ymcahouston.org

### Katie Devine Assistant Professor of Physics

- office: 208-459-5064cell: 507-261-9310
- email: kdevine@collegeofidaho.edu

## **Community References**

Nick Puccio Houston Director of Texas Episcopal Service Corps

- work: 713-353-2107cell: 713-497-7969
- email: npuccio@epicenter.org